lincolnchristian.edu 2017-04-07

# Privacy Statement

Lincoln Christian University is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the Lincoln Christian University website and governs data collection and usage. By using the Lincoln Christian University website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

**Collection of Your Personal Information**

Lincoln Christian University may collect personally identifiable information, such as your email address, name, home or work address, or telephone number. Lincoln Christian University may collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests, and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that may be collected by Lincoln Christian University. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses. This information is used by Lincoln Christian University for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Lincoln Christian University website.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Lincoln Christian University public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others.

Lincoln Christian University will not monitor electronic communications as a routine matter, but it may do so to ensure systems are being used in compliance with organizational policy and for purposes of maintaining the integrity and effective operation of the electronic communications systems.

All users should understand that privacy exists in electronic communications only to the extent at which the user protects the data being communicated.

Lincoln Christian University reserves the right to inspect and disclose the contents of electronic communications:

  * In the course of an investigation triggered by indications of misconduct or misuse
  * When a need to protect the health or safety of the organization or an individual is identified
  * As may be required to prevent interference with system operations
  * As may be necessary to locate information required for corporate business

Lincoln Christian University will inspect and disclose the contents of electronic communications when such action is necessary to respond to legal processes.

Lincoln Christian University encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Lincoln Christian University so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Lincoln Christian University is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Lincoln Christian University and Lincoln Christian University family of websites.

**Use of Your Personal Information**

Lincoln Christian University collects and uses your personal information to operate the Lincoln Christian University website and deliver the services you have requested. Lincoln Christian University also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Lincoln Christian University and its affiliates. Lincoln Christian University may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Lincoln Christian University does not sell, rent, or lease its customer lists to third parties. Lincoln Christian University may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (email, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Lincoln Christian University may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you emails or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Lincoln Christian University, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Lincoln Christian University does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

Lincoln Christian University keeps track of the web pages our customers visit within Lincoln Christian University’s website in order to determine what Lincoln Christian University services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Lincoln Christian University to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Lincoln Christian University websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal processes served on Lincoln Christian University or the website; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Lincoln Christian University; and (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Lincoln Christian University or the public.

**Use of Cookies**

The Lincoln Christian University website uses “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Lincoln Christian University pages, or register with Lincoln Christian University site or services, a cookie helps Lincoln Christian University recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Lincoln Christian University Web page, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Lincoln Christian University features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies, if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Lincoln Christian University services or websites you visit.

**Security of Your Personal Information**

Lincoln Christian University secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Lincoln Christian University secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

**Changes to This Statement**

Lincoln Christian University will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. Lincoln Christian University encourages you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how Lincoln Christian University is protecting your information.

**Contact Information**

Lincoln Christian University welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Lincoln Christian University has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Campus Technology via email or by phone at 217-732-3168, ext. 2305.
